Inventory of the Center for Democracy records
Hoover Institution Archives
Center for Democracy records
1985-2003
2004C30
Center for Democracy (Washington, D.C.)
924 manuscript boxes, 8 oversize boxes, 1 cubic foot box (389.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, studies, conference proceedings, minutes, correspondence, briefing books, press releases, financial records, printed matter, photographs, videotape, sound recordings, and memorabilia, relating to legislative, judicial and electoral processes in newly democratic countries.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Allen Weinstein papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
American private nonprofit foundation for the promotion of institutions of democratic government abroad.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, studies, conference proceedings, minutes, correspondence, briefing books, press releases, financial records, printed matter, photographs, videotape, sound recordings, and memorabilia, relating to legislative, judicial and electoral processes in newly democratic countries.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Democracy.; Legislative bodies.; Justice, Administration of.; Elections.; Videotapes; Phonotapes
Collection Contents
- Intellectual Property Conference; Bulgaria; Women in Development (Folder 1-4)
- Environmental Conference (Folder 5-9)
- Philippines, 1986-1987 (Folder 10-14)
- Soviet Union-miscellaneous (Folder 15-18)
- Latin American Consortium (Folder 19-23)
- International Judicial Conference (Folder 24-29)
- Philippine elections, 1987 (Folder 30-33)
- Latin American Consortium (Folder 34-38)
- Russia; Eastern Europe (Folder 39-41)
- Latin American Consortium (Folder 42-46)
- Board of Directors briefing books (Folder 47-50)
- Phonotapes (Folder 51-53)
- Nicaragua (Folder 54-57)
- Board of Directors briefing books; Latin American Consortium (Folder 58-62)
- Pre-1989 projects file (Folder 63-66)
- Guatemala (Folder 67-68)
- Courts of Ultimate Appeal Conference (Folder 69-70)
- Bahamas; Central American Legislative Training Project (Folder 72-72)
- Board of Directors briefing books (Folder 73)
- Videotapes (Folder 74-76)
- Council of Europe, 1986-1988 (Folder 77-80)
- Nicaragua (Folder 81-89)
- Various (Folder 90-91)
- Costa Rica; Nicaragua; Haiti (Folder 92-95)
- Gilman Environmental Conference; Europe (Folder 96-97)
- Russia (Folder 98-100)
- Africa (Folder 101-103)
- UNESCO; Council of Europe (Folder 104-106)
- Nicaragua (Folder 107-108)
- Africa (Folder 109-112)
- Videotapes (Folder 113-114)
- Budapest Conference, 1990 (Folder 115-117)
- Photographs (Folder 118-134)
- International Judicial Conferences, 1997-1998 (Folder 135-140)
- Historical Archives (journal) (Folder 141)
- Sandinistas (Folder 142-145)
- Guatemala; Central America (Folder 146-149)
- Haiti; Nicaragua (Folder 150-152)
- Women in Development conferences (Folder 153-155)
- Memorabilia; framed items (Folder 156-157)
- Ibero-American Judicial Exchange; Nicaragua (Folder 158-160)
- Women in Development; El Salvador (Folder 161-164)
- Central American Legislative Project (Folder 165-167)
- Administrative files (Folder 168-169)
- International Judicial Conference, Warsaw, 1998 (Folder 170-171)
- Nicaraguan Administrative Procedures Code Project (Folder 172-175)
- Costa Rican legislative project (Folder 176-178)
- Latin America and Europe-various (Folder 179-181)
- International legislative development projects; various (Folder 182-184)
- Costa Rican legislative project (Folder 185-187)
- Nicaragua election observation, 1996 (Folder 188)
- Miscellany (Folder 189-191)
- Nicaragua election observation, 1996 (Folder 192-193)
- Haiti (Folder 194-197)
- International Judicial Conference, 2002 (Folder 198)
- Board of Directors briefing books (Folder 199-201)
- Russia (Folder 202-207)
- Various (Folder 208-210)
- Florida election observation, various, 2002 (Folder 211-213)
- Russia (Folder 214-219)
- Haiti; Panama; El Salvador (Folder 220-221)
- Program para el Desarrollo Legislativo publications (Folder 222)
- Printed matter; miscellany (Folder 223-225)
- Nicaragua; printed matter; miscellany (Folder 226-229)
- Asia administrative files (Folder 230-232)
- Board of Directors briefing books (Folder 233-236)
- Election observation kits and hats (Folder 237-238)
- Photographs (Folder 239-243)
- Russia (Folder 244-245)
- Democracy and Peace (trilingual newspaper-English, Hebrew, Arabic) (Folder 246)
- International Judicial Conference, 1995 (Folder 247)
- International Judicial Conferences, 1995-1996 (Folder 248-249)
- International Judicial Conference, Washington, 1995 (Folder 250-251)
- Women in Development Conference, Strasbourg, 1992 (Folder 252-255)
- International Judicial Conference, 1995 (Folder 256-259)
- Guatemala; various (Folder 260-262)
- Central American legislative project (Folder 263-265)
- Nicaragua electoral process evaluation (Folder 266-267)
- Haiti (Folder 268-271)
- Sandinistas (Folder 272-273)
- Nicaragua legislative project (Folder 274-275)
- Nicaragua; Agency for International Development (Folder 276-278)
- Save the Children Federation (Russia) (Folder 279-281)
- Nicaragua (Folder 282-283)
- Framed certificates (Folder 284-285)
- Costa Rica legislative development grant (Folder 286-288)
- Women in Development; foundations; grants; various (Folder 289-291)
- El Salvador elections, 1991 (Folder 292-295)
- International Judicial Conference audiotapes, 1995 (Folder 296-299)
- Printed matter and various, 1988 (Folder 300-303)
- Costa Rica local office (Folder 304-306)
- Nigeria (Folder 307-308)
- Various (Folder 309-316)
- Commission on National Political Convention (Folder 317-318)
- International Judicial Conference, 1995 (Folder 319-322)
- Nicaragua; Guatemala; Central America (Folder 323-326)
- Videotapes (Folder 327-330)
- Democratic Federalism and Environmental Crisis Conference, Moscow, 1991 (Folder 331-332)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia) (Folder 333-335)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia)-Non-governmental organizations (Folder 336-339)
- Russia (Folder 340-342)
- Various (Folder 343-345)
- Save the Children Federation (Russia) (Folder 346-348)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia) (Folder 349-350)
- Russia; various (Folder 351-352)
- Environmental issues; Russia (Folder 353-355)
- Chemonics International; Rule of Law Project; Estonia; Central Asia (former Soviet Union) (Folder 356-359)
- Various; printed matter (Folder 360-362)
- International Judicial Conferences, 1994-1995; Russia (Folder 363-365)
- Conferences-various; Russia (Folder 366-368)
- Environmental issues; Russia (Folder 369-371)
- Chemonics International; Rule of Law Project; Central Asia (Folder 372-374)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia)-Non-governmental organizations (Folder 375-377)
- Environmental issues-Eastern Europe (Folder 378-380)
- The Center Magazine (Folder 381)
- Correspondence; Russia; various (Folder 382-385)
- Washington University Law Quarterly; Philippines; Democracy Program; various (Folder 386-387)
- Nicaragua (Folder 388-393)
- Printed matter; miscellany (Folder 394-395)
- Freedom of Information issues (Folder 396-398)
- U.S. Bicentennial; Latin America; China; various (Folder 399-401)
- Philippines; Africa; miscellany (Folder 402-404)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia) (Folder 405-407)
- Nicaragua (Folder 408-410)
- International Judicial Conferences, Strasbourg, 1993-1994 (Folder 411-413)
- International Judicial Conference, Washington, 1996 (Folder 414-416)
- Free Expression and Global Media Conference, American University, Washington, D.C., 1992 (Folder 417-418)
- Council of Europe; European Research Center (Folder 419-422)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia) (Folder 423-425)
- Central America (Folder 426-428)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia)-Non-governmental organizations (Folder 429-432)
- International Judicial Conferences, 1993-1994 (Folder 433-435)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia)-Non-governmental organizations (Folder 436-439)
- Allen Weinstein correspondence and publicity (Center for Democracy) (Folder 440-443)
- Civic Initiatives Program (Russia) (Folder 444-446)
- U.S. government funding; Estonia (Folder 447-449)
- Women in Development Conference, Strasbourg, 1992; miscellany (Folder 450-453)
- Videotapes (Folder 454-455)
- Various (Folder 456-457)
- U.S. Congress; Costa Rica (Folder 458-460)
- Chinese delegation to U.S. political conventions, 1988 (Folder 461)
- Conference on Transition to Democracy in Contemporary Europe, Warsaw, 1990; Latin America; Philippines (Folder 462-464)
- International Judicial Conferences, Strasbourg, 1993-1994 (Folder 465-468)
- U.S. domestic programs; various (Folder 469-471)
- Eastern Europe; various (Folder 472-473)
- Council of Europe; administrative files (Folder 474)
- Angola; Africa (Folder 475-478)
- International Judicial Conference, 1996 (Folder 479-481)
- Philippines; printed matter; various (Folder 482-484)
- Guatemala; Central America (Folder 485-488)
- Addresses (Folder 489)
- Central America (Folder 490-492)
- Various (Folder 493-495)
- Costa Rica; Chile (Folder 496-498)
- Nicaraguan elections, 1996 (Folder 499-501)
- Library of Democracy (Folder 502-504)
- Guatemala Project #104 (Folder 505-508)
- Haiti (Folder 509-512)
- Central America; Western Hemisphere Legislative Leaders Forum (Folder 513-516)
- Central America (Folder 517-520)
- Legal agreements; Consortium for Legislative Development (Folder 521-523)
- Board of Directors minutes and briefing books (Folder 524-527)
- Costa Rican legislative project (Folder 528-530)
- Latin America (Folder 531-532)
- Nicaraguan election observation grants (Folder 533-534)
- Various (Folder 535-536)
- Chilean newspapers (Folder 537)
- Videotapes (Folder 538-539)
- Various (Folder 540-545)
- Proper Role of an Intelligence Agency in a Democracy Conference, Sofia, 1992 (Folder 546-549)
- International Judicial Conference videotapes, 1995 (Folder 550-555)
- Democracy and Constitution-Making in Central and Eastern Europe Conference, Budapest, 1990 (Folder 556)
- Countries, especially China, former Soviet Union, Poland, Hungary, Bulgaria (Folder 557-560)
- Various (Folder 561-570)
- Phonotapes (Folder 571-573)
- International Judicial Conference videotapes, 1995 (Folder 574-577)
- E-mail printouts; various (Folder 578-581)
- Nicaraguan elections (Folder 582-585)
- Various (Folder 586-589)
- International Judicial Conference, Washington, 1996 (Folder 590-592)
- Central America; Council of Europe (Folder 593-594)
- Russia (Folder 595-597)
- Photographs; Chinese delegation to U.S. political conventions; Library of Democracy (Folder 598-599)
- Central American legislative project (Folder 600-601)
- Central American legislative manuals (Folder 602-604)
- Visit to China, 1988 (Folder 605-607)
- Miami-Dade County (Florida) election observation, 2002 (Folder 608-610)
- Central America; Western Hemisphere Legislative Leaders Forum; South Africa (Folder 611-613)
- Russia; Central America (Folder 614-616)
- Flags of Latin American countries (Folder 617-619)
- Commission on National Political Conventions (U.S.) (Folder 620-622)
- Videotapes; grant manuals; miscellaneous printed matter (Folder 623-625)
- Press articles and press releases-mainly Russia (Folder 626-629)
- U.S. Bicentennial; space programs; various (Folder 630-634)
- Space programs; South Africa (Folder 635-637)
- Latin America; Andean Conference; Indigenous Conference (Folder 638-642)
- Latin American Consortium (Folder 643-661)
- Latin America (Folder 662-680)
- Special events; International Medal of Democracy (Folder 681-684)
- Grants, conferences and visits-various; Florida election, 2002 (Folder 685-688)
- Various (Folder 689-695)
- Latin America (Folder 696-700)
- Chile (Folder 701-704)
- Council of Europe (Folder 705-707)
- Individual correspondence files (Folder 708-711)
- General correspondence (Folder 712-714)
- U.S. government correspondence; Women in Development (Folder 715-717)
- Central and Eastern Europe (Folder 718-722)
- Western Europe; Council of Europe (Folder 723-725)
- Asia; Middle East (Folder 726)
- Latin America (Folder 727-733)
- Press articles (Folder 734-736)
- International conferences-various (Folder 737-739)
- Asia (Folder 740-749)
- Latin America (Folder 750-756)
- Russia (Folder 757-758)
- Conference reports and manuals--various (Folder 759)
- Global Panel (Folder 760-762)
- Africa (Folder 763-764)
- Polish constitution facsimile (Folder 765)
- Central America (Folder 766-769)
- Central American publications (Programma del Desarrollo Legislativo and others) (Folder 770-773)
- Central America and Caribbean (mainly publications) (Folder 774-778)
- Central America; Haiti (Folder 779-785)
- Nicaragua; Central America; books (Folder 786-790)
- Russia; various; serial issues (Folder 791-793)
- International Judicial Conference correspondence, 1997 (Folder 794-798)
- South Africa (Folder 799-803)
- International Judicial Conference, 2000 (Folder 804-807)
- International Judicial Conference, 2001-2002 (Folder 808-811)
- International Judicial Conference; Democracy Medal; various (Folder 812-813)
- Regional projects-Europe and former Soviet Central Asia (Folder 814-823)
- Eastern Europe (including New Democracies Forum) (Folder 824-834)
- Turkey (New Democracies Forum) (Folder 835-837)
- Ukraine and other Eastern Europe (New Democracies Forum) (Folder 838-843)
- Administrative records (Folder 844)
- Russia (Folder 845-854)
- Central and Eastern Europe; International Judicial Conference; New Democracies Forum (Folder 855-858)
- Mexico; North American Free Trade Agreement; China (Folder 859-863)
- Board of Directors correspondence, meetings and briefing books (Folder 864-868)
- Conferences-miscellaneous; press releases; various (Folder 869-871)
- Guatemala (Folder 872-878)
- Panama (Folder 879-886)
- Nicaragua (Folder 887)
- Costa Rica (Folder 888-890)
- Nicaragua (Folder 891-894)
- Asociación de Técnicos Legislativos Centroamericanos (Folder 895)
- Nicaragua clippings (Folder 896-897)
- Panama clippings (Folder 898)
- Latin America (Folder 899-903)
- Asociación de Técnicos Legislativos Centroamericanos (Folder 904-908)
- Various (Folder 911-928)
- Library of Democracy Project. Russian-American dialogue (Folder 929)
- Eastern Europe and former Soviet Union (Folder 930)
- 1992 March conference tapes (Folder 931)
- 1992 March conference tapes (Folder 932)
- Governance in Space conference (Folder 932)
- Conference proceedings, 1985-1989 (Folder 933)